<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web on Andreas&#39; Blog</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in web on Andreas&#39; Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.anoff.io/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Hugo to render (nice) Asciidocs</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2019-02-17-hugo-render-asciidoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2019-02-17-hugo-render-asciidoc/</guid><description>While migrating my blog from Jekyll to Hugo I went down quite a rabbit hole. While setup and migration to Hugo was a breeze, I spent a lot of time making my .adoc formatted post work with the new blog. After working through several GitHub issues I ended up manipulating the DOM with Javascript to get admonitions working. It still doesn&amp;#8217;t feel right - but hey it works! 🤷‍♂️ This post will cover the steps I took in case I myself or anyone out there ever needs to do this again.</description></item><item><title>RBAC with Google Firestore</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2018-08-12-rbac-firestore/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2018-08-12-rbac-firestore/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This post will explain how to implement role based access control (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role-based_access_control&#34;&gt;RBAC&lt;/a&gt;) using the Google Firestore serverless database. Firebase and Firestore in particular with the concept presented in this post offers the most seamless integration of serverless infrastructure with a mobile client at this point. It has become my go to backend for all minor web apps I build.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building realtime apps with Vue and nodeJS</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2018-04-18-node-vue-websockets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2018-04-18-node-vue-websockets/</guid><description>Wanting to build a simple SPA as a side project I struggled with things that might annoy a lot of newcomers that do not want to go full vanilla. Which web framework, which style library, which server framework - and more importantly how does it all work together?
In this post we will put together a bunch of great tools out there to build a realtime web app with a few single lines of code.</description></item></channel></rss>