<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>databases on Andreas&#39; Blog</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/tags/databases/</link><description>Recent content in databases on Andreas&#39; Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.anoff.io/tags/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collect IoT data from Arduino in InfluxDB</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2021-01-send-iot-data-from-arduino-to-influxdb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2021-01-send-iot-data-from-arduino-to-influxdb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Did you add some fancy sensors to your Arduino board?
If you have internet connectivity via ESP8266 or similar chips you can easily collect and visualize your sensor readings using InfluxDB.
This blog post will cover how to send data from Arduino to InfluxDB Cloud (v2) but also to your self-hosted InfluxDB instance (v1).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting up Grafana on Raspberry Pi with Docker (compose)</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2021-01-howto-grafana-on-raspi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2021-01-howto-grafana-on-raspi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In previous blog posts I showed you &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-install-docker-raspi&#34;&gt;how to setup a Raspberry Pi with docker-compose support&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-run-influx-on-raspi-docker-compose&#34;&gt;how to run InfluxDB on your Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;.
This tutorial will add &lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com&#34;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt; to your Pi-stack and give you a complete monitoring setup.
The InfluxDB+Grafana stack is heavily used in DevOps scenarios but also extremely useful if you want to visualize any kind of timeseries data at home; power consumption, smart home events, computer uptime, amount of devices in your network, weather in your basement &amp;hellip; endless opportunities at your fingertips!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Running influxdb on Raspberry Pi using Docker compose</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-run-influx-on-raspi-docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-run-influx-on-raspi-docker-compose/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post will explain how you can setup influxdb (and the telegraf plugin) on your Raspberry Pi using docker-compose.
We will use the config-as-code to create a reproducible setup.
This is extremely helpful for hobby projects that you come back to every now-and-then because you can lookup exactly what you are running 😉&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>