<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iot on Andreas&#39; Blog</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/tags/iot/</link><description>Recent content in iot on Andreas&#39; Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.anoff.io/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running influxdb on Raspberry Pi using Docker compose</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-run-influx-on-raspi-docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-run-influx-on-raspi-docker-compose/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post will explain how you can setup influxdb (and the telegraf plugin) on your Raspberry Pi using docker-compose.
We will use the config-as-code to create a reproducible setup.
This is extremely helpful for hobby projects that you come back to every now-and-then because you can lookup exactly what you are running 😉&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to setup Raspberry Pi as home server with Docker support</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-install-docker-raspi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-install-docker-raspi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post will cover how to setup a Raspberry Pi with Docker support.
It will also cover some basic steps that will make it easier to work with your RasPi later on.
This setup will work completely without monitor/keyboard for your Raspberry but you need a LAN connection to it.
I wrote most commands so they are easily pastable and do not require too much interactive work - you should however carefully read what is going on with each of those commands before you fire them off!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Programming ESP and other Arduino compatible chips using VS Code on MacOS</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-programming-arduino-esp-with-vs-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2020-12-programming-arduino-esp-with-vs-code/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When you are developing microcontroller based projects as a hobbyist you often end up with the Arduino ecosystem and might be tempted to use their IDE.
This post will explain how you can develop, program &amp;amp; debug Arduino compatible devices using VS Code.
Even though this post is written with a MacOS walk-through it should be valid for other operation systems as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>