<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Architecture on Andreas&#39; Blog</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/tags/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in Architecture on Andreas&#39; Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.anoff.io/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced customization for Antora - PlantUML support &amp; custom UI</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2019-04-19-antora-plantuml-customize-ui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2019-04-19-antora-plantuml-customize-ui/</guid><description>This post will cover some slightly advanced steps for building a multi-repository Asciidoc documentation using Antora. My previous post blog.anoff.io/2019-02-15-antora-first-steps covered basics of Antora and how to migrate existing AsciiDoc files. In this post I will go through the steps of including content from another repository, building a custom UI and adding plantUML support to the (automated, dockerized) build.
plantUML supportOne of the most important things for me when it comes to software docs is the ability to show relationships and interactions using diagrams.</description></item><item><title>Converting existing AsciiDoc into an Antora project</title><link>https://blog.anoff.io/2019-02-15-antora-first-steps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.anoff.io/2019-02-15-antora-first-steps/</guid><description>After 2 years of working with the arc42 template in markdown, I spent the last few weeks learning about an asciidoc based site generator named Antora. The main reason for the interest in AsciiDoc was the fact that the limited feature set in markdown often impairs you while writing down complex things. But I had one problem; most of our documentation is scattered across multiple repositories as we try to keep the docs as close to the code as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>